

Rahul Motiyar

Interaction Designer Design team leader Digital & Hardware Prototype expert Phone +31 685145769

E-Mail rahulmotiyar@gmail.com

JOINING AVAILABILITY

August 2023

EDUCATION

Master's in Interaction Design IIT Bombay, India - 2013

Bachelor's in Technology Electronics, RTU, India - 2013

DESIGN AWARDS

IF Design Award 2020 Red Dot Design Award 2018 IF Design Award 2017

UX SKILLS

Interaction Design
User Research
Service design
Co-Create Facilitation
Visual Design
Rapid Prototyping
Agile methodology

UI TOOLS

Sketch Framer Adobe suite

3D MODELLING

AutoCAD Rhino Keyshot

MOVIE EDITORS

After effects Final Cut Pro

PROGRAMMING

Arduino Processing HTML/CSS

LANGUAGE

English, Hindi, Rajasthani

NATIONALITY

Indian, Residence permit holder In the Netherlands

DATE OF BIRTH

10 March 1988

ADDRESS

Jan Heurkensstrat 1, 5667 BL, Geldrop The Netherlands

PROFILE

I am an interaction designer with 10 years of experience in various domains like Healthcare, Serviceability, Informatics. I help organisation to strategically build meaningful products for their customers and users. I am very well versed with design tools, UX & serviced design skills for facilitating Co-creation workshops with customers & cross functional teams. I possess excellent physical & digital prototyping skills. I currently lead a design team on camera based innovation project in Philips, Netherlands.

EXPERIENCE

DESIGN LEAD & RESEARCHER, Philips design, Netherlands

NOV 2021 – CURRENT

- Driving Camera Based Innovations in CT & DXR as Lead designer
- Define Critical to Quality parameters along with the Advance development team.
- From Conceptualization to Prototyping ideas around automating workflows, motion detection & correction, provide real-time guidance to radiographer, reduce repeat scans caused due to poor positioning or motion artifacts.
- Facilitate Co-Create with customers, radiographers, scientists to generate ideas in a reduced quick 3-month innovation cycle which otherwise take up to a year.
- Generate workflows and research methodology for concept validation.
- Successful ICBE Submissions, Formative & Summative tests in realistic environment
- IP Generation and drive it to the submission with IP Council.

SR. USER EXPERIENCE DESIGN, Philips design, India

APR 2015 - OCT 2021

- Led a team of 5 UX & 2 Usability engineers to deliver Harmonized image acquisition experience to radiographers and operators in operating MRI, CT & DXR consoles.
- Facilitated various Co-Create workshops & remote sessions with clinical science, business units to gather user needs & system requirements of all imaging devices.
- Built low fidelity interactive mockups iteratively to run various clinical scenarios with users & customers.
- Negotiation with business, document decisions, buy-ins & trade-offs on confluence

USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER, Philips design, India

OCT 2013 - MAR 2015

- Studied role of Field service, Remote service & remote monitoring engineers and helped Philips serviceability team in improving Remote ticketing & Servicing tool.
- Improved UX, reduces the resolution time of tickets by 20% and thus products guarantee 99% uptime for healthcare devices installed across the globe by Philips.
- The product (IDM) received IF Design award in service design category in 2020.
- Working with design system, developer hand-off. Provided insights & created unavailable/evolving components which later fed into design system.
- Also responsible for improving various Healthcare informatics & Primary care & Monitoring products, Improved UX/UI for research-based products like Genomics informatics & Remote consultative critical care products.

RESEARCH ASSISTANT, National University of Singapore

JAN 2012 - APR 2012

- Conduct primary user-research in India and solutions around eye free & touch free interfaces.
- Came up with idea of Smart Medicine for chronic patients which reminds patients when it's time to take medicine.
- Build prototype and tested with 3 users & applied for IP submission.